Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello
1995-2011
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Bugliarello, George (Georgio Bugliarello-Wondrich)
RG.007
3
66 Linear Feet (59 boxes, 1 hard drive)
George Bugliarello was a visionary engineer, educator and administrator who was instrumental in reviving Polytechnic after its financial crisis in the early 1970s as well as developing a MetroTech Center, a university-industry park in downtown Brooklyn. The Chancellor's papers of George Bugliarello contain administrative and personal correspondence, memoranda, reports, publications, clippings produced by George Bugliarello, 13th President of then Polytechnic Institute of New York, during his tenure as Chancellor of Polytechnic University between 1994 and 2003 and his subsequent term as President Emeritus from 2004 to 2011.
Biographical Note
On October 15, 1973, George Bugliarello was inaugurated 13th President of what was then known as the Polytechnic Institute of New York. President Bugliarello took the reins at the most precarious time in Polytechnic's long history. Amid a national economic crisis in the 1970s, several private academic institutions in New York City were on the brink of collapse, including Polytechnic and New York University. On the brink of bankruptcy, New York University was forced to sell its University Heights campus in the Bronx to the City of New York. New York University also lost its School of Engineering in a merger with Polytechnic University of Brooklyn, which was then renamed Polytechnic University of New York. George Bugliarello, who served as President for between 1973 and 1994 and subsequently served as President emeritus and Chancellor until 2011, proved to be lucky Number 13 for the Institute and for the struggling neighborhood of Downtown Brooklyn.
Giorgio Bugliarello was born Georgio Bugliarello-Wondrich on May 20, 1927 to Spera Bugliarello-Wondrich and Colonel Federico Bugliarello Magnano di San Lio in Trieste, Italy. He graduated summa cum laude from the University of Padua where he earned a Dottore in Ingegneria (Dott.Ing.) in Civil Engineering. In 1954 he earned a Master's in Civil Engineering from the University of Minnesota on a Fulbright Scholarship. He then attended Massachusetts Institute of Technology's School of Engineering from 1956-1959, earning a doctorate in Civil Engineering and Hydronamics. George Bugliarello married his wife of over 50 years, Virginia Harding, in 1959. The couple had two sons, Nicholas and David.
Bugliarello taught Civil Engineering, Biotechnology and Bio-Engineering at Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) between 1959 and 1969, serving as founding directory of the Bio-Engineering program at CMU in 1964. In 1969, Bugliarello was appointed Dean of Engineering and Professor of Civil Engineering and Biotechnology at University of Illinois at Chicago Circle.
Despite a large deficit and bitterness and confusion among students and faculty of NYU's School of Engineering and Polytechnic Institute during the merger, Bugliarello made it his mission to revive Polytechnic by focusing on three goals: Increasing enrollment and academic programs through satellite campuses in Westchester and Long Island, increasing fundraising efforts and alumni outreach and develop a technological-industrial park in downtown Brooklyn. George Bugliarello was instrumental in the development of the MetroTech Center in Downtown Brooklyn which currently houses the NYU-Polytechnic campus. Bugliarello's success in combining academic, scientific and public development during his career was immortalized in the term he coined "Biosoma", a contraction of biology, society and machines. It's therefore unsurprising to learn that Bugliarello was instrumental in designing the seal of Polytechnic University – Homo Et Homines Opera Partes Naturae: Man and the works of man belong to nature.
George Bugliarello's professional and academic involvements and achievements are almost innumerable. He served as member and chair of American Society of Civil Engineers, American Society of Engineering Education, National Academy of Engineering, National Academy of Sciences, National Science Foundation, New York City Mayor's Commission on Science and Technology, and many others. Highlights include serving as founder and editor of the journal Technology in Society, president of Sigma Xi Scientific Research Society, founding fellow of the American Institute for Medical and Biological Engineering, fellow of dozens of scientific, academic and business societies, and receiving eight honorary degrees. Over his lifetime, Bugliarello published 17 books, over 350 articles, reports, and editorials and 18 newspaper articles. George Bugliarello died on February 18, 2011 in Port Washington, New York at the age of 83.
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into eight series. These series have been organized according to size:
Arrangement
Organizations
Subject Files
Publications
Polytechnic Institute
Audio-Visual Material
Speeches & Presentations
Correspondence
Photographs & Slides
Ephemera
Hard drive
Provenance
The Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello were transferred to the Archives of the Polytechnic Institute of New York University in 9 installments between September 2011 and January 2012. The papers were collected from Chancellor's Office in the Jacobs Building (Room 350) and George Bugliarello's home. The records in this collection were created and collected by George Bugliarello and his office staff in the Chancellor's Office.
Scope and Content Note
The Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello documents the activities of George Bugliarello, the 13th President of Polytechnic Institute of New York (1973-1994), who served as Chancellor from 1994 to 2003 and President Emeritus from 2003 to 2011. The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, financial records, published and unpublished writings, clippings, architectural floor plans, photographs, research notes, bound appointment books and digital files pertaining to the professional, scientific and academic activities of President George Bugliarello. The records in this collection highlight the extent of George Bugliarello's professional involvement in a wide array of scientific, academic and public organizations, committees and conferences. The bulk of the collection falls within the span of George Bugliarello's term as Chancellor (1994-2003), however the dates in this collection span from 1953 to 2011.
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection that contain sensitive or personal information and are restricted from use. Folders containing restricted material have been marked and will be separated from the collection prior to use by researchers.
Related Archival Material at Polytechnic Institute of New York University
RG.6: Guide to the Administrative Papers of President George Bugliarello
Sponsor note
This project was made possible by a generous grant from Violet J. Jacobs and the Jacobs Family Trust.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Virginia Bugliarello in 2011.
Research notes; Speeches; Photographs; Publications; Minutes; Pamphlets; Long Island, N.Y.; Westchester County (N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Gramercy Park (New York, N.Y.); Articles; Clippings; Trieste (Italy); Administrative records; Memoranda; Biosoma; Correspondence; Engineering; Business cards; Slides; Project 2061 (American Association for the Advancement of Science); Urban Sustainability; Compact discs; Audiocassettes; DVDs; Hard drives; Videotapes; Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Koch, Ed; Ratner, Bruce; Polytechnic Institute of New York University -- Center for Technology in Supply Chains and Merchandising; Marconi International Fellowship; National Academy of Engineering; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.); Alfred P. Sloan Foundation; Polytechnic Institute of New York. Center for Advanced Telecommunications Technology; Polytechnic Institute of New York; MetroTech Center; Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society; Dibner, Bern; National Research Council (U.S.). Board on Science and Technology for International Development; North Atlantic Treaty Organization; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.) -- Administration; Schillinger, A. George; Jacobs, Joseph J.; Mark, Herman F. (Herman Francis); American Society of Chemical Engineers; American Association for the Advancement of Science; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.) -- Office of the President
- Series I: Organizations, 4390
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, clippings, articles, meeting minutes and miscellaneous documents documenting George Bugliarello's role as member, trustee and elected official of a wide array educational, scientific, governmental and social organizations and associations.
  Arrangement Note
  This series is arranged alphabetically by organization. Large collections of folders from single organizations have been assigned to separate subseries. The remaining organizations have been grouped into the "Miscellaneous" subseries and have been arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries A: National Academies, 4393
    - Action Plan – Lance Davis, 2009; 4662 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Acactech Supply Chain, 2008 October; 4663 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Africa, 2004-2009; 4664 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A.I.D. – "The Role of U.S. Engineering Schools in Development Assistance", 1974; 4665 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 25th Anniversary, 1987; 4666 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting, 1988; 4667 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting, 1990; 4668 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting, 1999; 4669 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting, 2001; 4670 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting, 2003; 4671 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Autrey, Kevin – USAID Report, 2007; 4672 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dr. Baldev Raj – India, 2005-2006; 4673 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Belarus, 2004-2008; 4674 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bill Wulf, 2009; 4675 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bioengineering Steering Committee, 1997-1998; 4676 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blouke Carus, 2006; 4677 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Board on African Science Academy Development, 2004; 4678 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Board on Engineering Education, 1994; 4679 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Board on Infrastructure and the Constructed Environment, 1995; 4680 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Boright / Clogg / Boufford – Conference Call, 2009; 4681 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - BOSTID, 1992; 4682 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Board on Research Data and Information, 2009; 4683 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Bridge, 2007; 4684 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Brochure Review, 1989; 4685 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bruce Brown – Board on Army Science and Technology, 2010; 4686 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bruno Jarry – French Delegation, 2010; 4687 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - The Bridge, 2002-2007; 4688 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - The Bridge – World Trade Center, 2001; 4689 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - The Bridge, 1996-1999; 4690 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Foreign Secretary, 2005; 4691 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - George Bugliarello Election to N.A.E., 1986-1987; 4692 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - George Bugliarello Election to N.A.E., 1986-1987; 4693 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - George Bugliarello Election to N.A.E., 1986-1987; 4694 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - International Council of Academies of Engineering and Technological Sciences (CAETS), 2005-2007; 4695 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - CAETS - Tokyo, 2007 October; 4696 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - CAETS – Netherlands, 2008 June; 4697 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - CAETS – Calgary, 2009 July; 4698 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - CAETS – Copenhagen, 2010 June; 4699 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - CAETS – Miscellaneous, 2004-2005; 4700 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - China-America Frontiers of Engineering Symposium (CAFOE), 2009; 4701 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - CAFOE & CAE (Chinese Academy of Engineering), 2009 October; 4702 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - U.S. Frontiers of Engineering (F.O.E.), 2007-2008; 4703 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Canadian Academy of Engineering, 2008 June; 4704 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Canadian Academy of Engineering, 2005-2006; 4705 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Chauncey Starr – Project, 2003-2004; 4706 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - C.A.E. - China, 2006; 4707 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - C.A.E. – Chuck Vest, 2006-2009; 4708 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - C.A.E. – Promotional Material, 2003; 4709 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - C.A.E. - 10th Anniversary – Presentation / Paper, 2004; 4710 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Chilean Request, 2010; 4711 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Climate Change – President's Circle, 2008; 4712 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - China Trip, 2007; 4713 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - China – Dr. Xu Kuangdi – Honorary Degree, 2007; 4714 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Delegation – Cicerone, 2008 April 14; 4715 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chinese Academy of Engineering, 2004; 4716 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - C.A.E., 2007 April; 4717 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - China – KunMo Chung – Meeting, 2005-2008; 4718 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Committee on International Relations – Foreign Secretary – Conference Call, 2006 September 21; 4719 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Congratulations, 2005-2006; 4720 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Congratulations (New Members), 1988-1993; 4721 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Council, 1989; 4722 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Council Meeting, 1990 October; 4723 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Council – Foreign Secretary Report, 2005-2006; 4724 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Council – N.R.C. Governing Board, 2007 February; 4725 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Council / Governing Board, 2009 February; 4726 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Council – Annual Meeting, 2007 September; 4727 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Council – International Affairs Committee, Undated; 4728 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Critical Infrastructure Roundtable, 2005-2006; 4729 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Committee – K-12 Technology Education Standards, 1997; 4730 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Division on Engineering and Physical Sciences (DEPS) – Meeting, 2005 September; 4731 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - D.E.P.S. – Meeting, 2006 September; 4732 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - D.E.P.S. – Meeting, 2008 September; 4733 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - D.E.P.S. – Meeting, 2009 June; 4734 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - D.E.P.S. – Committee Meeting, 2009 September; 4735 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - D.E.P.S. – Committee Meeting, 2010 September; 4736 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - D.E.P.S. – Board on Infrastructure and the Constructed Environment – Denis Chamot, 2009-2010; 4737 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Department of State, 2005; 4738 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Dope, Dole and the Technological Fix", Undated; 4739 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Education Department, 1993-1994; 4741 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Eastern Europe, 1991; 5814 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Engineering Academy of Japan, 2009 March; 4740 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Engineering Academy of Japan, 2006; 4742 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "Engineering, Engineers and Engineering Education in the 21st Century" Workshop – A-E, 1989; 4743 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "Engineering, Engineers and Engineering Education in the 21st Century" Workshop – F-H, 1989; 4744 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "Engineering and Its Social Function", 1990-1991; 4745 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Engineer of 2020 Exhibition, 2004 July; 4746 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Energy Futures – Symposium, 2002 December 2; 4747 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - European Council of Applied Sciences and Engineering, EU-US Frontiers of Engineering – London, England, August 2010; 4748 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - European Union – Frontiers of Engineering, 2007-2009; 4749 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Frontiers of Engineering – Proposals Review, 2008; 4750 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Foreign Associates, 2005-2008; 4751 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Foreign Associates Meeting, 2004 May; 4752 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Foreign Associates Search, 2008 June; 5815 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Foreign Secretary Job Description, 2004; 4753 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Foreign Secretary – Miscellaneous, 2008-2009; 4754 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Foreign Secretary – National Research Council, Construction Inspection Program, 2007; 4755 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Foreign Secretary Report, 2007; 4756 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Foreign Secretary Report Note, 2005; 4757 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - France and European Union, 2005-2009; 4758 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Fundraising Solicitation, 1992; 4759 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - German-American Frontiers of Engineering Symposium – Oak Ridge, TN, 2010 April; 4760 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Global Dialogues on Emerging Science and Technology Committee – National Academies, 2004 November; 4761 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Georgia Delegation, 2010; 4762 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Germany Joint Conference, 2009; 4763 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Germany Joint Conference, 2008 October; 4764 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Golden Bridge Society, 2006; 4765 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Governing Board & Council – Irvine, California, 2005 February; 4766 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Grand Challenges in Engineering, 2008; 4767 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Indo-U.S. Frontiers of Engineering Symposium, 2006 March 2-4; 4768 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Indo-American Frontiers of Engineering Symposium, 2010 March 10-13; 4769 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Indian National Academy of Engineering, 2009; 4770 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Innovators: Designing the Future – DVD, 2007 April; 4771 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Karen Autrey - Inter-Academy Report Review, 2009; 4772 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - N.A.S. International Activities, 1997; 4773 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - International Affairs Advisory Committee – Agenda, 1988 August 1; 4774 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - International Affairs Advisory Committee, 1988-1989; 4775 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - International Affairs Advisory Committee, 1990-1992; 4776 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - International Institutions Workshop, 1988; 4777 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - International Scientist Visa Denial – Placid Rodriguez, 2006 February; 4778 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Iraq – John Boright, 2009; 4779 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Israel, 2007; 4780 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Italy, 1989; 4781 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Japan American Frontiers of Engineering, 2006; 4782 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - JAFOE - Paolo Alto, 2007 November; 4783 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - JAFOE – Japan, 2008 November; 4784 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - JAFOE – Irvine, CA, 2009 November; 4785 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - JAFOE, 2005 November; 4786 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Korea, Undated; 4787 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Liaisons, 2006 September-December; 4788 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - London – Foreign Associates Meeting, 2004 May; 4789 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Madrid – Georgetown University Center for Intercultural Education and Development, 2006; 4790 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Matrix – Academies' Activities, 2007-2008; 4791 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Megacities, 2001-2002; 5816 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Metrics – International Conference on Industrial Environmental Performance Metrics, 1998; 4792 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Metrics Conference, 1999; 4793 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Mexico, 2009; 4794 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Mexican Academy of Sciences, 2007; 4795 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Mexican Liaison, 2005-2008; 4796 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Mexico – Jerry Rivaro, 2005; 4797 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1990; 4798 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-2007; 4799 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Nominating Committee, 2008 October; 4800 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Nominating Committee, 2010; 4801 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Nominating Committee - Meeting, 2010 November 8; 4802 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - New Memberships & Congratulations, 1994; 4803 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - NAE-K – Korea – Intellectual Property, 2005-2010; 4804 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - NAS Committee on Human Rights – Cuba, 1997; 4805 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - National Meeting – Irvine, CA, 1992 February; 4806 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - National Academies – Committee on International Programs, Undated; 4807 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - National Committee on Science Education, 1992; 4808 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - National Academies – Presidents' Circle, 2004; 4809 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - National Committee on Science Education Standards and Assessment –Executive Editorial Committee, 1994; 4810 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Non-Governmental International Engineering Organizations Workshop, 1988; 4811 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - N.R.C. - Governing Board, 2010 May; 4812 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - N.R.C. - Board on Sustainable Development, 1993, 1997; 4813 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - N.R.C. – Board on Engineering Education, 1993; 4814 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - N.R.C. – Committee on International Organizations and Programs, 1993-1996; 4815 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - N.R.C. – Commission of Geosciences, Environment and Resources, 1994; 4816 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - N.R.C. – Committee on Science and Education (COSE) K-12, 1996-2000; 4817 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board – Woods Hole, MA, 2010 August; 4818 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - N.R.C. – Global NAE Council, 2009 May; 4819 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board – Committee on International Programs, 2004; 4820 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - N.R.C. - Report – U.S. / Iran, 2002; 4821 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board – Woods Hole, MA, 2009 July; 4822 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - N.R.C. – Committee on Knowledge Assessment, 1997 March; 4823 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - N.R.C. – National Science Education Standards, 1994; 4824 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - N.R.C. – Myron F. Uman – Proposal, 1995; 4825 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - N.R.C. – Recycling Cities, 1995; 4826 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - N.R.C. – US-Japan Committee, 1998; 4827 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - N.R.C. – Knowledge Assessment, 1995-1999; 4828 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board and Committee on International Programs, 2006 November; 4829 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board, 2009 November; 4830 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board – NAE Council – Annapolis, MD, 2008 May; 4831 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board Meeting, 2010 November; 4832 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - N.R.C. – Research Doctorate Survey, 2007; 4833 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - N.R.C. – U.S. – Japan Engineering Education, 1994, 1998; 4834 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - N.R.C. – Center for Science, Mathematics and Engineering Education – Harold Pratt, 1997; 4835 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - N.R.C. – Governing Board – Committee on International Programs, 2007; 4836 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - National Science Board Meeting, 2006 March; 4837 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Norwegian Academy of Technological Sciences, 2004; 4838 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Professor Siro Polo Padolecchia, 2002-2007; 4839 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Presidents' Circle, 2006; 4840 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Presidents' Circle – Washington, DC, 2008 June; 4841 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Princeton Regional Meeting, 2008 March; 4842 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - President's Circle – Irvine, CA, 2007 November; 4843 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The Presidents' Circle – Woods Hole, MA, 2007 June; 4844 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Presidential Search, 1993; 4845 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - President Kuangdi Xi Nomination, 2005; 4846 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Program Advisory Committee, 1992; 4847 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Public Infrastructure & Economic Growth – Annual Meeting, 1991; 4848 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Rethinking Today's Cities, 2000-2001; 4849 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Role of U.S. Engineering Schools, 1974; 4850 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Committee on Counterterrorism Challenges for Russia and the U.S., 2002-2007; 4851 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Russia – Moscow Correspondence – 1, 2003-2004; 4852 (Box 4, Folder 31)